Bradlee Ward, Sound Designer and Broadway Associate

www.BradWard.net Info@BradWard.Net

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

Award-winning theatrical sound designer and composer
25+ years' experience in professional theatre
10+ years' experience in education
Knowledge of sound playback software (QLab, LCS, MaxMSP ...)
Digital editing and recording (Pro-Tools, DP, Logic ...)
Experienced system designer and consultant
2d CAD drafting and 3d modeling and scheduling in Revit
Follow instructions/meet deadlines
Work well under pressure
Collaboration with team members

Administrative, budgeting, communication, and organizational skills

EDUCATION

Yale School of Drama, M.F.A. in Sound Design Miss Julie

A Splash of Nutmeg in Milk

Merchant of Venice A Book of Two

FREELANCE SOUND DESIGNER/COMPOSER AND BROADWAY ASSOCIATE

(Please visit www.bradward.net for a sample portfolio of work.)

Manhattan Theatre Club, Broadway Choir Boy* Tony Nominated for Best Sound

Roundabout Theatre, Broadway Bernhardt Hamlet*

Mabou Mines, NYC Faust II*

Atlantic Theatre Company, NYC The Mother*

Cirque du Soleil, Las Vegas The Beatles LOVE (lead system tech)

Rattlestick Playwrights Theater, NYC Lewiston and Clarkston*

Bristol Riverside Theatre, Bristol PA The Rivals the Musical

On Golden Pond Time Stands Still

An Enemy of the People

Lost in Yonkers Pride and Prejudice

NYC Public Library, Grand Army Plaza The Brooklyn Gaze

Classical Theatre of Harlem, NYC Fit for a Queen

Manhattan Theatre Source, NYC You Can't Get Uptown on the Downtown Train

New York City Fringe Festival

You've Never Done Anything Unforgivable

Columbia University, NYC Baal

New York University, NYU Super Sound Sunday (regular presenter)

Yale Cabaret Theatre, New Haven, CT In the Heart of America

(L)imitation of Life Funeral Games

You've Never Done Anything Unforgivable

Without/Sin

Belmont University, Nashville Singin' in the Rain

Les Misérables Into the Woods Le Nozze di Figaro

Lipscomb University, Nashville Death of a Salesman

Darkhorse Theatre, Nashville Spoon River Anthology

Nashville Children's Theatre Number the Stars

Williams College, Williamstown, MA Company

Nevada Conservatory Theatre/UNLV, Las Vegas Artist in residence

Fiddler on the Roof

You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown

Manchester Central Hall Queen Elizabeth's Diamond Jubilee

Celebration

UK Tour *42nd Street the Musical+*

Wyndham's Theatre, West End, London Abigail's Party+

Old Vic Tunnels, London Our Days of Rage+

Orpheus & Eurydice, a Myth Underground+

Theatre 503. London PMQ

High Tide Festival, Suffolk, UK PMQ

Hampstead Theatre, London .45

Mountview Academy, London 42nd Street

Secret Garden

The Underbelly/Edinburgh Fringe Festival The Jammer

Cockroach Theatre, Las Vegas The Methuselah Tree

* denotes associate role

+ denotes project manager role

RELATED EXPERIENCE

DLR Group | Westlake Reed Leskosky, NYC 2015 - Present Senior Audiovisual and Theatrical Systems Designer

Belmont University, Nashville 2012 - 2013 Assistant Professor of Audio Engineering Technology

Blitz Communications, London, 2010 - 2012 Sound Project Manager

Acoustic Dimensions, NYC, 2008 - 2009 Sound and AV Systems Designer

Cirque du Soleil/The Mirage, 2006 - 2008 Lead Audio Tech for *The Beatles LOVE*

AFFILIATIONS, PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT, AND HONORS

United States Institute for Theatre Technology, Vice Commissioner of Sound Commission, regular presenter and conference volunteer, grant recipient, and award recipient

Theatrical Sound Designers and Composers Association (US), founding member, education committee

Association of Sound Designers (UK), founding member

Prague QA, Featured design 2019 US exhibit, prior exhibitor, Sound Kitchen 2015 team member

World Stage Design, exhibit designer/curator for Sound Kitchen 2021 and 2017, award recipient

AVIXA (InfoComm), Certified Technology Specialist - Design (CTS-D)

OISTAT, theatre sound working group

Lipscomb University Faculty/Staff Member of the Semester award (selected by student body)

Opryland All Star award for the mixing of *The Big Broadcast*